[
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4273A)\nWhich one of the displayed cloud forms is representative of altocumulus lenticularis?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (1).pdf",
        "question_number": 37
    },
    {
        "question": "East Africa is situated in the zone of\n",
        "answer": "Tropical climate\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "subarctic climate\n",
        "choicethree": "snow climate\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (1).pdf",
        "question_number": 42
    },
    {
        "question": "Convective currents are most active on warm summer afternoons when winds are\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "moderate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (10).pdf",
        "question_number": 21
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types is found at high levels?\n",
        "answer": "cl\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "AS\n",
        "choicethree": "CU\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (10).pdf",
        "question_number": 42
    },
    {
        "question": "Convective currents are most active on warm summer afternoons when winds are\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "moderate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (11).pdf",
        "question_number": 6
    },
    {
        "question": "An altimeter adjusted to 1013 hPa ites an altitude of 3600 ft. Should this altimeter\nbe adjusted to the local QNH value of 991 hPa, the altitude indicated would be\n\n",
        "answer": "3006 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "2922 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "4194 ft\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (11).pdf",
        "question_number": 35
    },
    {
        "question": "From which direction do the trade winds blow, in the southern hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "NE\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (12).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thermal index would predict the best probability of good soaring conditions?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (13).pdf",
        "question_number": 11
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following causes echoes on meteorological radar screens?\n",
        "answer": "Hail\n",
        "choiceone": "Water vapour\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "Any cloud\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (13).pdf",
        "question_number": 41
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10901A)\nWhat is the average temperature difference from ISA at FL 390 between Madrid and\nDhahran?\n",
        "answer": "-1\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "+5\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "+2\u00b0C\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (13).pdf",
        "question_number": 42
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather condition can be expected when moist air flows from a relatively warm\nsurface to a colder surface?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "Increased visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convective turbulence due to surface heating.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (14).pdf",
        "question_number": 7
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weather condition can be expected when moist air flows from a relatively warm\nsurface to a colder surface?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "Increased visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Convective turbulence due to surface heating.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (15).pdf",
        "question_number": 15
    },
    {
        "question": "East Africa is situated in the zone of\n",
        "answer": "Tropical climate\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "subarctic climate\n",
        "choicethree": "snow climate\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (15).pdf",
        "question_number": 42
    },
    {
        "question": "Convective currents are most active on warm summer afternoons when winds are\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "moderate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (16).pdf",
        "question_number": 20
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following types of cloud is most likely to produce heavy precipitation ?\n",
        "answer": "NS.\n",
        "choiceone": "cs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (16).pdf",
        "question_number": 36
    },
    {
        "question": "The temperature at FL 140 is -12\u00b0C. What will the temperature be at FL 110 if the ICAO\nstandard lapse rate is applied ?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "-18\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "\u201c15\u00b0C.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (19).pdf",
        "question_number": 35
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thermal index would predict the best probability of good soaring conditions?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (21).pdf",
        "question_number": 20
    },
    {
        "question": "The temperature at FL 140 is -12\u00b0C. What will the temperature be at FL 110 if the ICAO\nstandard lapse rate is applied ?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "-18\u00b0C.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "\u201c15\u00b0C.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (21).pdf",
        "question_number": 33
    },
    {
        "question": "The decrease in temperature, per 100 metres, in a saturated rising parcel of air at lower\nlevels of the atmosphere is approximately\n",
        "answer": "0.6\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "1.5\u00b0C\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (21).pdf",
        "question_number": 36
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-2056A)\nOf the four radio soundings, select the one that indicates ground fog:\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (21).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following types of cloud is most likely to produce heavy precipitation ?\n",
        "answer": "NS.\n",
        "choiceone": "cs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (22).pdf",
        "question_number": 39
    },
    {
        "question": "From which direction do the trade winds blow, in the southern hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "NE\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (22).pdf",
        "question_number": 41
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following causes echoes on meteorological radar screens?\n",
        "answer": "Hail\n",
        "choiceone": "Water vapour\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "Any cloud\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (22).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a characteristic of stable air?\n",
        "answer": "Stratiform clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fair weather cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (27).pdf",
        "question_number": 15
    },
    {
        "question": "Which force, in the Northern Hemisphere, acts at a right angle to the wind and deflects it\nto the right until parallel to the isobars?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "Centrifugal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure gradient.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (27).pdf",
        "question_number": 24
    },
    {
        "question": "An air temperature of -30\u00b0C at the 300 hPa level over central Europe in summer is\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "within +-5\u00b0C of ISA\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "very low\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (27).pdf",
        "question_number": 34
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4376A)\nSelect from the map the average wind for the route Shannon - Lisboa at FL 290.\n",
        "answer": "360/80\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "190/75\n",
        "choicethree": "340/90\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (27).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "East Africa is situated in the zone of\n",
        "answer": "Tropical climate\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "subarctic climate\n",
        "choicethree": "snow climate\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (28).pdf",
        "question_number": 41
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thermal index would predict the best probability of good soaring conditions?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (29).pdf",
        "question_number": 13
    },
    {
        "question": "An air temperature of -30\u00b0C at the 300 hPa level over central Europe in summer is\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "within +-5\u00b0C of ISA\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "very low\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (29).pdf",
        "question_number": 34
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying at FL 45 (OAT 6\u00b0C) obtains a reading of 1860 ft on its radio altimeter\n(ground elevation 3090 ft). What is the value of the QNH, to the nearest hPa, at that\npoint?\n",
        "answer": "1030\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "1013\n",
        "choicethree": "1042\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (29).pdf",
        "question_number": 35
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4376A)\nSelect from the map the average wind for the route Shannon - Lisboa at FL 290.\n",
        "answer": "360/80\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "190/75\n",
        "choicethree": "340/90\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (29).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying at FL 45 (OAT 6\u00b0C) obtains a reading of 1860 ft on its radio altimeter\n(ground elevation 3090 ft). What is the value of the QNH, to the nearest hPa, at that\npoint?\n",
        "answer": "1030\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "1013\n",
        "choicethree": "1042\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (3).pdf",
        "question_number": 30
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thermal index would predict the best probability of good soaring conditions?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "20\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (30).pdf",
        "question_number": 16
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a characteristic of stable air?\n",
        "answer": "Stratiform clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fair weather cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (30).pdf",
        "question_number": 22
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4273A)\nWhich one of the displayed cloud forms is representative of altocumulus lenticularis?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (30).pdf",
        "question_number": 39
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flying at FL 45 (OAT 6\u00b0C) obtains a reading of 1860 ft on its radio altimeter\n(ground elevation 3090 ft). What is the value of the QNH, to the nearest hPa, at that\npoint?\n",
        "answer": "1030\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "1013\n",
        "choicethree": "1042\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (31).pdf",
        "question_number": 30
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a characteristic of stable air?\n",
        "answer": "Stratiform clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fair weather cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (32).pdf",
        "question_number": 29
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following causes echoes on meteorological radar screens?\n",
        "answer": "Hail\n",
        "choiceone": "Water vapour\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "Any cloud\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (32).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following types of cloud is most likely to produce heavy precipitation ?\n",
        "answer": "NS.\n",
        "choiceone": "cs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (33).pdf",
        "question_number": 39
    },
    {
        "question": "From which direction do the trade winds blow, in the southern hemisphere?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "NE\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (33).pdf",
        "question_number": 41
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following causes echoes on meteorological radar screens?\n",
        "answer": "Hail\n",
        "choiceone": "Water vapour\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "Any cloud\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (33).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "An air temperature of -30\u00b0C at the 300 hPa level over central Europe in summer is\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "within +-5\u00b0C of ISA\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "very low\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (4).pdf",
        "question_number": 32
    },
    {
        "question": "The decrease in temperature, per 100 metres, in a saturated rising parcel of air at lower\nlevels of the atmosphere is approximately\n",
        "answer": "0.6\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "1.5\u00b0C\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (4).pdf",
        "question_number": 36
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following types of cloud is most likely to produce heavy precipitation ?\n",
        "answer": "NS.\n",
        "choiceone": "cs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (4).pdf",
        "question_number": 39
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-2056A)\nOf the four radio soundings, select the one that indicates ground fog:\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (4).pdf",
        "question_number": 42
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Surface Analysis Chart, the soli\ncalled\n\nines that depict sea level pressure patterns are\n",
        "answer": "isobars.\n",
        "choiceone": "isogons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (5).pdf",
        "question_number": 6
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thermal index would predict the best probability of good soaring conditions?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "20\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (5).pdf",
        "question_number": 16
    },
    {
        "question": "Which force, in the Northern Hemisphere, acts at a right angle to the wind and deflects it\nto the right until parallel to the isobars?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "Centrifugal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pressure gradient.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (5).pdf",
        "question_number": 30
    },
    {
        "question": "An altimeter adjusted to 1013 hPa ites an altitude of 3600 ft. Should this altimeter\nbe adjusted to the local QNH value of 991 hPa, the altitude indicated would be\n\n",
        "answer": "3006 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "2922 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "4194 ft\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (5).pdf",
        "question_number": 33
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud types is found at high levels?\n",
        "answer": "cl\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "AS\n",
        "choicethree": "CU\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (5).pdf",
        "question_number": 35
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-10901A)\nWhat is the average temperature difference from ISA at FL 390 between Madrid and\nDhahran?\n",
        "answer": "-1\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "+5\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "+2\u00b0C\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (5).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "Which thermal index would predict the best probability of good soaring conditions?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (6).pdf",
        "question_number": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Surface Analysis Chart, the soli\ncalled\n\nines that depict sea level pressure patterns are\n",
        "answer": "isobars.\n",
        "choiceone": "isogons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (6).pdf",
        "question_number": 17
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a characteristic of stable air?\n",
        "answer": "Stratiform clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fair weather cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (7).pdf",
        "question_number": 29
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following causes echoes on meteorological radar screens?\n",
        "answer": "Hail\n",
        "choiceone": "Water vapour\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "Any cloud\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (7).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following causes echoes on meteorological radar screens?\n",
        "answer": "Hail\n",
        "choiceone": "Water vapour\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "choicethree": "Any cloud\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (8).pdf",
        "question_number": 42
    },
    {
        "question": "Convective currents are most active on warm summer afternoons when winds are\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "moderate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "strong.\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (9).pdf",
        "question_number": 18
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a characteristic of stable air?\n",
        "answer": "Stratiform clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fair weather cumulus clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (9).pdf",
        "question_number": 24
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 050-4376A)\nSelect from the map the average wind for the route Shannon - Lisboa at FL 290.\n",
        "answer": "360/80\n",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "190/75\n",
        "choicethree": "340/90\n",
        "file_name": "MET\\met atpl (9).pdf",
        "question_number": 43
    }
]